Fernando Ropero

PhD in Computer Science

Results-oriented researcher with 5+ years of artificial intelligence experience applied in the robotics field, including optimization methods and evolutionary algorithms. Motivated to explore and acquire new knowledge to create autonomous technologies that improve society's life quality.



Ĭ	linkedin.com/in/fropero	github.com/FRopero
Q	Madrid, España	fropero.com
\bowtie	fernando.ropero@uah.es	+34697874337

SKILLS

Organizational Skills Teamwork Communication Skills Problem-solving skills Artificial Intelligence Methods

Statistics Algorithms Autonomous Vehicles

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Applied Researcher University of Alcalá

09/2017 - Present Alcalá de Henares, Spain

Achievements/Tasks

- Formulated and implemented a novel path planning algorithm for efficient cooperative multi-robot exploration in Mars terrains.
- Created a task planning algorithm for parcel deliveries by a cooperative truck-drones system.
- Awarded cum laude for his thesis.
- Co-director of 1 Phd's student.

Visiting PhD Student

Technische Universiteit Delft

02/2019 - 08/2019 Achievements/Tasks

• Devised a mathematical method for cooperative routing between truck and drones.

- Evaluated discrete optimization methods for cooperative routing.
- Built an autonomous controller for multi-robot cooperation in uncertain terrains.
- Worked with other researchers in efficient energy distribution in smart grids.

Postgraduate Researcher

University of Alcalá

09/2015 - 09/2017

Alcalá de Henares, Spain

Delft, The Netherlands

- Achievements/Tasks

 Integrated an artificial intelligence system into an unmanned aerial vehicle for terrain exploration.
- Devised a computational geometry algorithm for smart clustering in multi-robot scenarios.
- Created evolutionary algorithms for solving routing problems of cooperative multi-robot systems.
- Supervised 2 Bachelor's students and 1 Master's student.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Entry-Level Researcher University of Alcalá

09/2014 - 09/2015

Achievements/Tasks

- Alcalá de Henares, Spain
- Designed and built the hardware and software of an unmanned aerial vehicle for artificial intelligence applications.
- Implemented a ground control station for the assessment of autonomous controllers for robotic applications.
- Collaborated in several robotic projects inside the Intelligent Systems Group of the University of Alcalá.

EDUCATION

PhD, Computer Science University of Alcalá

09/2016 - 11/2020 Alcalá de Henares, Spain

Master's Degree in Space Research

University of Alcalá

09/2015 - 09/2016 Alcalá de Henares, Spain

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

University of Alcalá

09/2010 - 09/2015 Alcalá de Henares, Spain

CERTIFICATES

British Council, Advanced English (09/2016 - 09/2017)

Advanced English course given by the British Council at the University of

Introduction to Pyhton and the framework Django (07/2012 - 08/2012)

Course given at the University of Alcalá

General English Intership (07/2013 - 08/2013)

English course given by the ATC Language School in Bray, Ireland.

Course on IT security assessment (07/2011 - 08/2011)

Course given at the University of Alcalá

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

HONOR AWARDS

Second prize at the 8th UAH Technology-Based Business Creation Ideas Contest (02/2015 - 02/2015)

University of Alcalá

INTERESTS

Sports

Friends

Technology